### **Catherine Yun**

Address: 6649 Neptune Ct. San Jose, CA 95120 E-mail: cathieyun@gmail.com Phone: (408) 528-5217

### **Objective**

As a highly driven student, academically and socially, I strive to apply the skills I learn in the classroom to the real world, so that I can make a difference in others' lives. In order to achieve this goal, I involve myself in the community in as many ways as I can, giving back by sharing my knowledge and inspiring others.

#### **Profile**

- Flexible and versatile able to adapt to and work hard under many different circumstances. Have a talent for grasping new material quickly, such as new technology, a new language, a new instrument, a new sport, and new tasks and responsibilities.
- Hard working and driven dedicated to long-term commitments to an activity or goal, despite short-term obstacles.
- Organized able to stay on top of many tasks and assignments at once, good at setting deadlines, scheduling, and taking care of every detail.

Skills Summary	
Tri-lingual: English, Chinese,	<ul> <li>Speak and understand Chinese and English fluently.</li> <li>Experience translating Chinese/Eng, Eng/Chinese, Spanish/Eng.</li> <li>Can speak, read, and write Spanish, but not completely fluent.</li> </ul>
Spanish Effective Social Networking Agent	<ul> <li>Experience with social change through online media: Facebook, Twitter, MySpace, Tumblr, Wordpress (CUBE experience)</li> </ul>
Leadership Skills	<ul> <li>Experience with leadership in school and volunteer activities</li> <li>Often organize informal activities, such as study sessions, exercise outings, and team bonding events.</li> </ul>
Lab Research Skills	<ul> <li>Proficient in lab equipment (experience in AP Chemistry, AP Biology, summer internship in genetics lab).</li> </ul>
Good with children	<ul> <li>Experience with teaching (English, Piano, Debate, Tutoring).</li> <li>Friendly and Engaging (Residents' Assistant, Daycare, Activities)</li> </ul>
Computer Savvy	<ul> <li>Good knowledge of basic office programs (word, excel, etc.)</li> <li>Basic programming (C++, Pascal, Logo, Python, ImageJ)</li> </ul>
Education	
August 2012	<ul> <li>Massachusetts Institute of Technology (MIT)</li> <li>Accepted by MIT with major in Bioengineering and minor in Business Management.</li> <li>Will participate in internships and research with professors.</li> </ul>
September 2008 –	Saint Francis College Preparatory High School

National Merit Finalist and a Varsity Student-Athlete for 3 years. Academic High Honors award for 4 years, and the 4.0 award.

May 2012

- A member in the California Scholarship Federation, National Honor Society, and National Society of High School Scholars.
- 4.56 weighted GPA, ranked top 20 in class, 2350 SAT I score.

## September 2005 – June 2008

### **Challenger Middle School**

- Straight-A student, graduating at the top of the class.
- President of the Student Council.
- Co-founder and chief editor of the school's magazine.
- 1<sup>st</sup> place in the district-wide "Daughters of the American Revolution History Essay Contest", school-wide science fair competition, and the "Young Authors Book Project".

# September 2002 – December 2009

#### **San Jose Unified School District Chinese School**

- Attended the weekly weekend Chinese School classes, which taught Chinese listening, speaking, reading, and writing as well as Culture, Arts, and History.
- 1<sup>st</sup> place in the Chinese Poetry Recitation Competition (2009), and the Pinyin Transcribing Competition (2010)

#### **Professional Experience**

#### **July 2010**

### **Global Education Summer Camp: Shanghai EXPO**

Position: English Teacher, Residents' Assistant, Translator

- Taught English to local middle / elementary school students.
- Helped with residential life, by living in and supervising dorms.
- Lead tours and supervised groups at the Shanghai EXPO.
- Translated between English, for the American college student teachers, and Chinese, for campers and staff.

#### **June 2010**

### Shepherd's Field Orphanage, Beijing

Position: English Teacher, Child Care / Rehabilitation, Translator

- Taught English to orphans and staff members.
- Translated between English for American doctors and volunteers, and Chinese for the orphans and staff.
- Helped with child care, meals, activities, physical therapy.

### July – August 2011

### **Centrillion Biosciences (Genetics Analysis Start-up)**

Position: Research Assistant, Summer Intern

- Laboratory experiments: primed, synthesized DNA microfibers.
- Data analysis: imaged samples with a fluorescent microscope.
- Process optimization: wrote a program to make analysis of image data more efficient and accurate.

# December 2009 – present

#### **Piano Teacher**

• 3 young beginner students, weekly hour-long piano lessons.

# December 2010 - present

#### **Freelance Musician**

- For-hire musician, plays piano for entertainment at events.
- Perform for private parties and social events: Christmas and engagement parties, school-wide "Christmas at Our House" fundraiser, Pit Orchestra in *The Sound of Music* musical

### **Volunteer Experience**

### September 2010 – March 2012

### **Sunday Friends: The Working Alternative to Charity**

Position: Teen Leader of Photography

- Teach financial responsibility to poor families: run a mock bank, explain basic financial concepts and duties.
- Translate between English and Spanish for Hispanic families, so they can communicate with volunteers and complete tasks.
- Coordinated photography for publicity and fundraising.

### September 2010 – March 2011

### **Villa Sienna Nursing Home**

Position: Musician, Physical Therapy Assistant, basic care

- Played piano to entertain the elderly: concerts and sing-alongs.
- Feeding, talking to, walking and physical therapy with elderly.

# September 2010 – present

### **California Scholarship Federation**

Position: Tutor, Teacher's Assistant

- Helped with Math and Science tutoring.
- Graded papers, helped teachers organize (e.g. attendance)
- Helped organize, run, staff academic events (e.g. Open House)

### June 2010 -August 2011

### **CUBE Club (CUring oBEsity)**

Position: Co-founder, teen leader for social networking

- Wrote blueprint for the club, organized the structure.
- Social networking: Facebook, Twitter, Tumblr, Wordpress posts, updates, and self-advertising.
- Organized local outings and events.

# Awarded in 2010 and 2011

### **Brother Eamon Schaffer Service Award**

• Recognition for more than 100 hours of outstanding community service (volunteering) per year, awarded for 2 years.

#### **Extracurricular Activities**

# September 2009 - present

### **Speech and Debate: Public Forum**

Position: Team Captain, Travelling Varsity Team

- Plan practice rounds, team meetings, contact guest lecturers.
- Prepare extensively for nationally competitive travel tournaments, win awards to increase team ranking.

### Awards and Recognition:

- Ranked 55<sup>th</sup> in the United States in Public Forum Debate.
- Finalists at Berkeley Invitational at UC Berkeley (2011).
- Most Improved Debater (2011).

# September 2009 – present

#### **Math Club**

Position: President (2011-2012), Vice President (2010-2011)

- Plan activities: guest lectures, puzzles, fundraisers, competitions
- Publicity: Math handouts, daily math joke announcements.

### Awards and Recognition:

- Certificate of Distinction: American Mathematics Competition 12
- Certificate of Recognition, Qualifier: American Invitational Mathematics Examination.

# September 2009 – present

### Newspaper

Position: Contributing Writer, Staff Writer, Copy Editor

- Pioneered, and am editor for, Science and Technology section.
- Write articles for the monthly newspaper issues.

# September 2009 – present

### Symphonic, Marching, and Jazz Bands

Position: lead pianist, lead keyboard, 2<sup>nd</sup> alto saxophone

- Performed in parades and field shows with Marching Band
- Toured in Italy, L.A., Bay Area with Symphonic and Jazz Band.

## Awards and Recognition:

• 1<sup>st</sup> place in Lincoln Review of Champions, and Folsom Jazz Festival

# September 2002 – present

#### **Classical Piano**

Position: piano student, currently recording an album

- Yearly Certificate of Merit Testing (currently Level 10, teacher certification), Honor Recitals (qualified 2009 and 2010).
- Studio recording for album weekly classes, daily practice.